<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-12-02T16:10:59-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LYSZT - Portfólios e Projetos Relevantes</title><subtitle>Welcome to the portfolio of João Luís Almeida Santos (Lyszt Kaldwin), a skilled Developer &amp; Designer. Explore UI/UX design, web &amp; software solutions, and video production services tailored to elevate your business. Discover recent projects and learn about João&apos;s experience in the tech industry. Powered by Lygon Xin.</subtitle><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><entry><title type="html">Embraer - Analysis of the Supply Chain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Embraer-Analysis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Embraer - Analysis of the Supply Chain" /><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Embraer-Analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Embraer-Analysis/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="embraer-an-investment-analysis-07302025">Embraer: An Investment Analysis (07/30/2025)</h1>

<h2 id="embraer-in-focus-an-overview-of-the-brazilian-aerospace-company">Embraer in Focus: An Overview of the Brazilian Aerospace Company</h2>

<p>Embraer, with over fifty years of operation, is an aerospace company that manufactures aircraft and operates in various segments. The company is active in Commercial Aviation, Executive Jets, Defense &amp; Security, and future air mobility. Its mission is to “shape the future of air mobility,” which reflects its commitment to innovation, safety, and sustainability.</p>

<p>As of July 30, 2025, the question for investors concerns Embraer’s growth potential.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Articles/embraer.jpg" alt="Embraer planes going by the sky." /></p>
<h2 id="embraers-portfolio-of-operations">Embraer’s Portfolio of Operations</h2>

<p>To understand Embraer’s potential, it is important to analyze the variety of its operations. The company is not limited to aircraft manufacturing; it develops a range of activities spanning various sectors. The Commercial Aviation, Executive Jets, and Defense &amp; Security areas are the company’s main revenue drivers. Additionally, Agricultural Aviation, with ethanol-powered and ANAC-certified aircraft, demonstrates an attention to sustainable solutions. Embraer Equipment Division (EDE) produces and controls important components such as landing gear and hydraulic systems. In the Advanced Air Mobility segment, Eve Air Mobility, with its eVTOL (electric vertical take-off and landing vehicle) projects, positions Embraer at the forefront of urban air mobility. In the field of Technology and Defense, companies like Atech, Visiona, and Aguas Azuis, which participates in the construction of naval frigates, demonstrate Embraer’s capability in high-tech and security sectors. Finally, OGMA offers maintenance services, and Nidec Aerospace supplies electric motors for new aircraft. This diversification of operations contributes to multiple revenue streams and helps mitigate risks, increasing the company’s resilience to market fluctuations.</p>

<h2 id="embr3-performance-signs-of-market-optimism">EMBR3 Performance: Signs of Market Optimism</h2>

<p>The recent performance of Embraer’s shares (EMBR3) has been notable, especially in July 2025. On July 30, EMBR3’s year-to-date and last twelve-month profitability surpassed that of major technology companies such as Nvidia, Microsoft, Meta, Amazon, Alphabet, Apple, and Tesla. This is a relevant indicator for investors. On the same day, shares rose over 10%, with a 10.93% gain. The reason was the White House’s confirmation that aircraft, in addition to energy and orange juice, were excluded from an additional 50% tariff on Brazilian imports, initially announced by Donald Trump on July 9. This exclusion represents a significant benefit for Embraer’s exports to the U.S. These recent events indicate renewed market optimism regarding Embraer, driven by solid financial results and the reduction of important commercial risks.</p>

<h2 id="challenges-and-opportunities-in-the-supply-chain">Challenges and Opportunities in the Supply Chain</h2>

<p>Embraer, as a large industrial company, faces challenges in its complex supply chain. However, these challenges can also present strategic opportunities. Regarding Carbon Fiber Composites, the market is growing, driven by demand for lighter and more efficient aircraft. Innovations in low-cost materials and recycling are promising, and Embraer needs to ensure access to these materials, considering the trend of domestic supply in the U.S. to avoid tariffs.</p>

<p>As for Future Engines, the transition to electric, hybrid, and hydrogen propulsion is a reality. The next-generation propulsion market is booming, and Embraer, through Eve Air Mobility, is involved in this transition. Environmental regulations and U.S. tariffs are accelerating this shift.</p>

<p>In the Battery sector, lithium-ion batteries are essential, and the market is growing. However, there is competition from new technologies, such as sodium-ion batteries, and investments in recycling and domestic manufacturing, like LG Chem’s Tennessee factory, indicate a dynamic scenario that Embraer must monitor.</p>

<p>Regarding Avionics and Semiconductors, onboard electronics are becoming more advanced. Partnerships for maintenance and modernization, such as with CMC Electronics, are important. Demand for semiconductors increases with electrification, but the global supply chain still faces challenges like component counterfeiting and the need for “green semiconductors.”</p>

<p>Concerning Hydraulics and Marine Propulsion, although there is a trend towards electro-mechanical systems, innovations in hydraulics continue to seek efficiency. In the naval sector, Embraer, through Aguas Azuis, benefits from the growing adoption of hybrid and electric propulsion systems, driven by decarbonization goals.</p>

<p>For Radiation-Hardened Electronics, which are crucial for Visiona in space systems, demand is increasing. The shortage of testing capacity in the U.S. is a challenge, but new technologies are emerging to solve it.</p>

<p>Finally, the Rare Earths market is a point that requires attention. It faces supply restrictions, rising prices, and geopolitical tensions, such as the possible mining ban in Myanmar and China’s export restrictions. The search for heavy rare-earth-free magnets, like those developed by Proterial, and investments in recycling, like those by Apple and MP Materials, are important for supply chain stability. Embraer, which uses these materials, needs to monitor this situation.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Articles/embraer2.jpg" alt="Embraer plane landing." /></p>

<p>Embraer, as of July 30, 2025, presents a favorable scenario for investors. Its strategic diversification, which goes beyond traditional aviation, positions it in markets with potential of growth, such as advanced air mobility and defense. Recent financial performance, surpassing other large companies, and the positive resolution regarding U.S. tariffs are indicators of a favorable moment.</p>

<p>However, investors should be aware of the challenges in global supply chains, especially the volatility in the rare earths market. Embraer’s ability to innovate and secure access to essential materials, while leveraging sustainability and electrification trends, will be a determining factor for its long-term success.</p>

<p>In summary, Embraer appears to be in a good position for a new growth cycle. For those seeking an investment in a high-tech sector with a focus on innovation and resilience, the Brazilian company could be an interesting option. However, as with any investment, continuous research and risk analysis are always fundamental.</p>

<h1 id="kairos-insight-iii">Kairos Insight III</h1>

<p>This analysis of Embraer, which I conducted on July 30, 2025, leverages data collected and processed by Kairos Insight 3, a comprehensive data collection and scraping program I developed from the ground up. My work on Kairos Insight 3 involved architecting its robust backend using Python and Django, where I integrated and configured libraries such as requests for making HTTP requests, feedparser for RSS feed aggregation, BeautifulSoup for parsing HTML content, readability for extracting clean article text, dateparser for flexible date parsing, and GNews for efficient news aggregation. I designed and implemented the data collection and analysis scripts, ensuring their efficiency and reliability for web scraping and processing diverse data sources. Furthermore, I developed its integrated AI component through custom Python modules (e.g., collector/Analysis/AI.py), which I engineered to provide advanced capabilities for summarizing web pages, extracting structured data, and performing in-depth analysis of company activities, offering a deep dive into market signals and logistical dependencies. On the frontend, I built the user interface with React and TypeScript, leveraging Vite for a fast development experience and Tailwind CSS for a modern and responsive design, ensuring efficient data presentation and a seamless user experience.</p>]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="MARKET ANALYSIS" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embraer: An Investment Analysis (07/30/2025)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LYSZT - A modern and interactive portfolio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/LYSZT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LYSZT - A modern and interactive portfolio" /><published>2025-01-07T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/LYSZT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/LYSZT/"><![CDATA[<p>LYSZT is my personal portfolio: a fast, maintainable site that highlights case studies without getting in the way.</p>

<h2 id="objectives">Objectives</h2>
<p>Navigation stays simple and consistent across posts and case studies. Performance is prioritized on desktop and mobile with lightweight assets, and content updates are straightforward—no layout surprises when adding new work.</p>

<h2 id="build-and-content">Build and content</h2>
<p>The site uses a minimal grid-based layout, a restrained color palette, and generous whitespace for readability. Structured sections—hero, case summaries, CTAs—let new entries slot in cleanly, while optimized images and compressed assets keep the experience snappy.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/14cd34e1-e4fc-48b6-b2ca-194ded0cb6b4" alt="Page composition and imagery" /></p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b28fc10d-31eb-4e82-8b1d-e00eae7ac10e" alt="Landing and sign-in treatments" /></p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/28b5969b-7f71-44cd-9eb7-7685fc4b7ff8" alt="Supporting visuals" /></p>

<hr />]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="PORTFOLIO PIECE" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[LYSZT is my personal portfolio: a fast, maintainable site that highlights case studies without getting in the way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Principles for making figures for research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ArticleDesign/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Principles for making figures for research" /><published>2024-11-14T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ArticleDesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ArticleDesign/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="knowing-how-to-sell-your-research-the-importance-of-design-in-academic-papers">Knowing How to “Sell” Your Research: The Importance of Design in Academic Papers</h1>

<p><img src="/assets/img/3darticle.jpg" alt="Beautiful 3d render made for a research paper" /></p>

<p>Knowing how to sell is one particularly important aspect of anything you do, write or create. There is no better way than convincing your customer that you product is top-notch than doing so by using aesthetics and design. Research shows that 75% of a consumer’s judgment about a product is based on its appearance, with design playing a crucial role in influencing purchasing decisions (Source: Adobe). Furthermore, products with good aesthetics are often perceived as higher quality and more valuable, leading to a 30% increase in consumer engagement and a 20% higher likelihood of purchase (Source: Forbes). So, it becomes obvious: beauty doesn’t just apply to businesses and trade, it’s actually present everywhere. When you go for a job interview, when you try to convince your friend to come join your Minecraft server and build with you, or, as is the subject of this blog post, when you’re writing an article, a research paper, and you want to ** get your paper published **.
But the principle of “design” extends beyond business. It influences how we present ideas, persuade others, and communicate messages.</p>

<p>In scientific writing, design also plays a pivotal role in shaping how your work is perceived. The layout of a research paper, the clarity of figures, and the use of visual elements such as graphs or tables can significantly impact how readers engage with the content. Studies have shown that beautiful scientific articles are more likely to be cited and have higher readership. A paper that is easy to navigate, with visually appealing formatting and concise, well-structured sections, encourages readers to engage more deeply. Poor design, on the other hand, can lead to misunderstandings or cause readers to disengage prematurely, undermining the impact of even the most groundbreaking research.</p>

<h1 id="uiux-in-scientific-writing-clarifying-the-role-of-design">UI/UX in Scientific Writing: Clarifying the Role of Design</h1>
<p>With this said, it might also be important to consider that figures are ought to pass down a message. Don’t use figures nonsensically, use them to reinforce an idea or increase understanding. It’s basically UI/UX—User Interface and User Experience—which, although primarily associated with digital products, is just as relevant when presenting academic work. UI refers to the design elements that help structure the content and make it easy to navigate, while UX focuses on ensuring a positive experience for the reader, allowing them to engage with the material efficiently and intuitively. Every figure should reinforce an idea, clarify a concept, or provide additional insight into your research. In this way, the integration of UI/UX principles in your paper’s design not only improves the presentation but also enhances the reader’s understanding and engagement with the content.”</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>UI (User Interface)</strong> refers to the design elements that make content easy to navigate and interact with. In a research paper, this includes how well the text, figures, graphs, and tables are organized, the consistency of formatting, and how readable the paper is as a whole.</li>
  <li><strong>UX (User Experience)</strong> focuses on ensuring that the reader has a positive, efficient experience when engaging with the paper. It’s about making sure that the information flows logically, the figures are intuitive, and the design helps the reader to grasp the content easily. A positive UX in a research paper means the reader can focus on understanding the research without being distracted by confusing layouts or poorly presented data.
Another valuable way to refine the UX of your research paper is to gather feedback through user testing. Just as companies conduct A/B testing to understand how different versions of a product resonate with their audience, you can apply a similar approach to your paper by showing it to friends, colleagues, or even unfamiliar readers. This external feedback can highlight areas where the flow or design of your paper might be confusing, too dense, or difficult to follow. By making adjustments based on their input, you can improve the overall user experience of your paper, ensuring that your ideas are communicated as clearly and effectively as possible.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’d like to mention one good scientific article designer, <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2009.09134">Colin Ophus</a>. He makes good choices of colours and remarkably interesting designs that connect well to a paper that might be considered quite complex (Multibeam Electron Diffraction). The figures help the reader understand and visualize those not so easy to comprehend ideas, and that’s what figures are all about!</p>

<p>But what to use in order to create the best possible articles? Now that we’ve established the importance of design, here are some tools to help you create high-quality visuals for your paper:</p>

<ul>
  <li>For 3D modeling, Blender is an excellent open-source tool that allows you to create detailed, high-quality visual representations of complex concepts.</li>
  <li>Python offers a range of libraries such as Matplotlib and Seaborn for creating dynamic, customizable charts and graphs that can effectively convey statistical information.</li>
  <li>If you’re looking for something more advanced, Unity or Unreal Engine can be used for immersive 3D visualizations that could turn your research into an interactive experience. With this, your crush your competitors.</li>
  <li>Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign) is a great tool for refining layouts, creating clean vector graphics, and designing polished figures. Am I going too far?</li>
  <li>But you don’t need to go all-in on professionality. Canva is super easy and has tons of templates to make graphs and images look polished without much work.</li>
  <li>Google Sheets or Excel can help you whip up some charts and graphs to show off your numbers. Automatic, mind you.
Here’s the complete list if you’re an advanced user and want the best stuff there is. You can go look for it.</li>
  <li>Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Bokeh, Mayavi, Dask, Pandas, TensorFlow, PyTorch, PyOpenGL, Pygame, Unity, Unreal Engine, VTK, Mayavi, Dash, Streamlit.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Below I have left a documentary in case you have the interest of diving in further into the subject.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="DISCUSSION" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing How to “Sell” Your Research: The Importance of Design in Academic Papers]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">THERAPY WITH LEX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Lex/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THERAPY WITH LEX" /><published>2024-01-01T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Lex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Lex/"><![CDATA[<p>This was a marketing site for therapist and coach Lex E. Santi. The brief: present services, books, and long-form writing in a fast, credible, and easy-to-maintain way.</p>

<p>Focus areas were clear pathways for coaching and clinical supervision, a responsive layout tuned for mobile visitors, and easy updates through structured content blocks rather than ad-hoc HTML.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Web/Lex/1.png" alt="Clinical supervision visual for Lex" /></p>

<p>This section packages the clinical supervision offer with concise copy and iconography, keeping the message approachable for licensed professionals.</p>

<p>Structured sections for services, testimonials, and CTAs keep edits consistent. Optimized assets and typography help pages load quickly and stay readable on phones, and the forms/CTAs are instrumented so we can see which services attract clicks.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Web/Lex/2.png" alt="Poetry carousel design for Lex" /></p>

<p>An accessible carousel showcases poetry titles with clear navigation, generous spacing, and typography that suits the literary tone of the work.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Web/Lex/3.png" alt="Lex site hero and mobile treatments" /></p>

<p>Additional layouts show the hero treatment and responsive mobile views used across the site. Structured content blocks and lightweight assets keep edits simple and performance high.</p>

<hr />]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="PORTFOLIO PIECE" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a marketing site for therapist and coach Lex E. Santi. The brief: present services, books, and long-form writing in a fast, credible, and easy-to-maintain way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LYGON - A Service Agency Dedicated to Design, Animation, and the Arts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Lygon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LYGON - A Service Agency Dedicated to Design, Animation, and the Arts" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Lygon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Lygon/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="lygon---creative-production-and-delivery">LYGON - Creative Production and Delivery</h1>

<p>Lygon Xin is the umbrella for my video, animation, and supporting web work. I handle branding, editing, and delivery for a range of clients—from influencers defining their voice to teams in Canada and the United States that need reliable promo and internal videos. The toolkit stays consistent: After Effects, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, and lightweight web builds that keep reels fast to load.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Logobackground.png" alt="Lygon Logo" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The first iterations of Lygon’s brand were created back in 2014, setting the foundation for years of creative growth.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h2 id="a-visual-evolution-from-2016-to-2021">A Visual Evolution: From 2016 to 2021</h2>

<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/13qCYubhscI" title="Lygon intro 2016 version" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fjJKdGJ5cN8" title="Lygon intro 2021 version" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p><em>“Lygon’s opening sequences have evolved significantly. Compare the dynamic simplistic 2016 version to the polished 2021 iteration.”</em></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="working-with-influencers-and-businesses">Working with Influencers and Businesses</h2>

<p>I build promo, branding, and internal communications videos with a tight review loop—script, storyboard, V1/V2/final—so feedback is specific and turnarounds stay quick. Deliverables ship with thumbnails and captions for web and social. Work ranges from branding and promotional cuts tuned for target audiences to internal comms pieces that stay on-message and concise. Collaborations span influencers, entrepreneurial teams, and established businesses across Canada and the United States, all following the same disciplined process so clients always know what’s next.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Design/mockup.jpg" alt="Design Mockup" /></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="exploring-entertainment-and-wild-storytelling">Exploring Entertainment and Wild Storytelling</h2>

<p>Lygon Xin is also a platform for unconventional storytelling. The YouTube miniseries <em>Chodo and Deton</em> dives into immortality, clone-making, and multiverse travel—kept on track with the same production discipline (clear checkpoints, versioned cuts, and purposeful visual choices).</p>

<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XJf9m81MkAI" title="Chodo and Deton episode 1" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O5K_f5ET98M" title="Chodo and Deton episode 2" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KtLxMTNSyOQ" title="Chodo and Deton episode 3" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you have time to spare and a love for absurd comedy, this series is worth a watch. For client work, the same structured process applies—just with a different tone and purpose.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="PORTFOLIO PIECE" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[LYGON - Creative Production and Delivery]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MACTAB - How interactive design can help your business</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Mactab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MACTAB - How interactive design can help your business" /><published>2021-08-05T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Mactab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Mactab/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="mactab-interactive-configurator-for-partitions">MACTAB: Interactive Configurator for Partitions</h1>

<p>MACTAB manufactures industrial floor-to-ceiling partitions. I built a browser-based configurator so sales and clients could explore fabrics, panels, locks, blinds, handles, and glass options without needing custom renders for every request.</p>

<p><img src="https://mactab.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logo-mactab-novo.png" alt="Mactab Logo" /></p>

<p><strong>Focus</strong>
Guided steps keep selections valid and obvious. Real-time previews reflect material and hardware choices, and exports stay clean for manufacturing handoff.</p>

<p>Users pick fabrics, panels, locks, blinds, handles, and glass, seeing changes immediately instead of waiting on static renders. Inline validation blocks incompatible mixes while presets give sales a sensible starting point, and the flow stays fast enough to run on-site with customers.</p>

<p>That translated into fewer back-and-forth cycles for quotes—a single PDF plus snapshot covers the spec. Sales reps use the same data-driven options, keeping outputs consistent, and prospects engage longer because they can experiment safely without breaking constraints.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Web/Mactab/1.jpg" alt="Design Example 1" /></p>

<p>The UI guides users through options, validating combinations and updating previews immediately. Exports capture selections so the factory team can act without back-and-forth.</p>

<h3 id="video-demonstration">Video Demonstration</h3>

<div class="video-embed">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OFG6XV8jaBE" title="MACTAB interactive configurator demo" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Portfolio/Web/Mactab/2.png" alt="Design Example 2" /></p>]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="PORTFOLIO PIECE" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MACTAB: Interactive Configurator for Partitions]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BLADE ZENON - A collaborative game made by its players</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Zenon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BLADE ZENON - A collaborative game made by its players" /><published>2015-03-01T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Zenon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Zenon/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="blade-zenon-how-a-collaborative-project-managed-to-create-a-game-managed-by-its-users">Blade Zenon: How a Collaborative Project Managed to Create a Game Managed by Its Users</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Website for Blade Zenon:</strong> A website for a MMORPG project from 2015</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This was my first experience shipping something end-to-end. At 12 I built a Unity prototype, spun up a forum, and attracted 100+ active members. It never launched commercially, but it taught me how to design community features, ship fast, and respond to user feedback.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/N6e0iGa.png" alt="Blade Zenon Concept Art" /></p>

<hr />

<p>Research has shown that when people feel they have a stake in the outcome of a project, their level of engagement increases. This is particularly true in online communities, where members are more likely to contribute to projects they feel are shaped by their input.</p>

<p>The idea that the success of a project hinges on the contributions of its users is supported by self-determination theory in psychology. It suggests that people are motivated when they feel competent, autonomous, and connected to others. Blade Zenon’s collaborative design allowed members to experience all three. They weren’t just passive participants; they had a direct hand in how the game developed, which likely drove their continued involvement.</p>

<p>In game development, especially in a collaborative setting, feedback loops are crucial. These loops not only help improve the game’s mechanics but also foster a sense of ownership among users. The process I went through with Blade Zenon—the cycle of receiving feedback, adjusting the design, and implementing new ideas—mirrors the concept of continuous improvement found in agile development.</p>

<p>It’s an approach that emphasizes constant iteration, and in the context of Blade Zenon, it ensured the game adapted and evolved based on real user experiences. By staying responsive to feedback, the project could refine its design and make meaningful changes in real-time. The forum architecture itself was lightweight: themed templates, clear hierarchy, and simple moderation tooling to keep discussions productive.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/1ayvgvp.png" alt="Blade Zenon Forum" /></p>

<hr />

<p>Blade Zenon was an online game that featured a community-driven environment, where players could engage in various activities such as forming guilds and participating in discussions about game lore and mechanics. I moderated contributions, merged good ideas, and published changelog-style updates so everyone saw their input reflected in the build.</p>

<p>Members provided ideas, and I executed them. It was a game made by its players, and the lesson still applies: ship quickly, listen carefully, and let users see their fingerprints on the product.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/xQnrPVI.png" alt="Blade Zenon Memories" /></p>

<hr />]]></content><author><name>João Luís Almeida Santos</name></author><category term="PORTFOLIO PIECE" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blade Zenon: How a Collaborative Project Managed to Create a Game Managed by Its Users]]></summary></entry></feed>